linuxhint.com 2019-06-03

# Privacy Policy – Linux Hint

### 1\. Our Commitment to Privacy.

This notice describes our Privacy Policy. Our privacy policy explains how Linux Hint (“Linux Hint”) collects, uses, and protects the personal information obtained through the use of our Linux Hint website https://www.linuxhint.com (“Site”) and the services available through the Site (collectively, “Services”). Through the Services we provide an educational platform complete with articles and videos about open source technology. By visiting the Site or using any of our Services, you agree that your personal information will be handled as described in this Privacy Policy. Your use of our Site or Services, and any dispute over privacy, is subject to this Policy and our Terms of Use, including its applicable limitations on damages and the resolution of disputes. The Linux Hint Terms of Use are incorporated by reference into this Privacy Policy.

### 2\. What Information is Collected. 

We collect information about you directly from you and from third parties, as well as automatically through your use of our Site or Services. Under the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), the Sustainable Linux Hint LLC is a Data Controller. 

(a) Information We Collect Directly From You. Certain areas and features of our Site and Services require providing some personal information. If you wish to send us an email, we will ask for your name and email address.

(b) Information We Collect Automatically. We automatically collect information about your use of our Services through cookies, web beacons, and other technologies. We combine this information with other information we collect about you. Please see the section “Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms” below for more information.

Site:  
o domain name;  
o your browser type and operating system;  
o web pages you view; links you click; your IP address;  
o the length of time you visit our Site and or use our Services;  
o the referring URL, or the webpage that led you to our Site.

(c) We do not collect any types of Sensitive Data from our users. Sensitive Data includes any personally identifiable information pertaining to: race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union memberships, genetic or biometric data, health or mortality, and sex life or sexual orientation. Please immediately notify us if you have accidentally submitted any Sensitive Data and we shall promptly remove such information.

### 3\. How and When the Information is Used. 

The personally and non-personally identifiable information we collect is used for administering our business activities. No personally identifiable information is collected, sold, gathered or used for any other purpose.

### 4\. How We Share Your Information. 

We may share information in the following circumstances:

a. Service Providers. We will not sell, trade, or rent your personally identifiable information to others. However, we do provide some of our services through contractual arrangements made with affiliates, service providers, partners and other third parties (“Service Providers”). Our Service Providers include Mail Chimp. We use Mail Chimp to store email contact information and send all emails to our users. We and our Service Partners may need to use some personal information in order to perform tasks between our respective sites, or to deliver services to you.

b. Business Transfers. If we are acquired by or merged with another company, if substantially all of our assets are transferred to another company, or as part of a bankruptcy proceeding, we may transfer the information we have collected from you to the other company.

c. In Response to Legal Process. We also may disclose the information we collect from you in order to comply with the law, a judicial proceeding, court order, or other legal process, such as in response to a court order or a subpoena.

d. To Protect Us and Others. We also may disclose the information we collect from you where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Use or this Privacy Policy, or as evidence in litigation in which we are involved.

e. Aggregate and De-Identified Information. We may share aggregate or de-identified information about users with third parties for marketing, advertising, research or similar purposes.

### 5\. How We Protect Your Information. 

To protect your personal identifiable information, we take reasonable precautions and follow industry standard SSL/TLS end-to-end encryption of data in transit to make sure it is not inappropriately lost, misused, accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed. All other information we collect may be stored in perpetuity through our database, unless we receive a request by you to remove such information. We store all information through our internal database, but your name and email is also stored through Mailchimp. The information is only accessible by Linux Hint administrators for internal use and is stored in perpetuity until requested to be removed.

Although we have implemented commercially reasonable precautions to protect the information we collect from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction, please be aware that despite our best efforts, no data security measures can guarantee 100% security. You should take steps to protect against unauthorized access to your password, phone, and computer by, among other things, signing off after using a shared computer.

### 6\. Third-Party Advertising

Advertising on our Site is based on cookies and similar technology. We use personalized online advertising on our Services. This allows us to deliver more relevant advertising to people who visit our Site. It works by showing you advertisements that are based on your browsing patterns and the way you have interacted with our Site. It then shows you ads which we believe may interest you.

When you use our Services, some of the cookies and similar technology we place on your device are advertising cookies, so we can understand what sort of pages you are interested in. We can then display advertising on your browser based on these interests. For instance, if you have been viewing a lot of food related videos, we may show you more advertisements for food and drink.

We do not collect or use information such as your name or email address for personalized online advertising.  
We may also show you advertising on our Site based on your browsing patterns on other websites or mobile applications that we have obtained from our advertising partners.

Online retargeting is another form of online advertising that allows us and some of our advertising partners to show you advertising based on your browsing patterns and interactions with a website or mobile applications away from our Services.

### 7\. Our Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms

We and our third party service providers or advertisers use cookies and other tracking mechanisms to track information about your use of our Site or Services. We may combine this information with other personal information we collect from you.

Cookies. Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser for record-keeping purposes. Some cookies allow us to make it easier for you to navigate our Site and Services, while others are used to enable a faster log-in process or to allow us to track your activities at our Site and Service. We use three types of cookies: session, persistent and advertising cookies.

a. Session Cookies. Session cookies exist only during an online session. They disappear from your computer when you close your browser or turn off your computer. We use session cookies to allow our systems to uniquely identify you during a session or while you are logged into the Site. This allows us to process your online transactions and requests and verify your identity, after you have logged in, as you move through our Site.

b. Persistent Cookies. Persistent cookies remain on your computer after you have closed your browser or turned off your computer. We use persistent cookies to track aggregate and statistical information about user activity, and to display advertising both on our Site and on third-party sites.

c. Advertising Cookies. Cookies that are used to collect information about your visit to our Site, the content you have viewed, the links you have followed and information about your browser, device and your IP address. We have set out more details on this below.

d. Disabling Cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can edit your browser options to block them in the future. The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your computer from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Visitors to our Site who disable cookies will be able to browse certain areas of the Site, but some features may not function.

e. Clear GIFs, pixel tags and other technologies. Clear GIFs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on your computer’s hard drive, clear GIFs are embedded invisibly on web pages. We may use clear GIFs (a.k.a. web beacons, web bugs or pixel tags), in connection with our Site, App and Services to, among other things, track the activities of Site visitors and App users, help us manage content, and compile statistics about Site and App usage. We and our third party service providers also use clear GIFs in HTML emails to our customers, to help us track email response rates, identify when our emails are viewed, and track whether our emails are forwarded.

### 8\. Third Party Analytics

We use automated devices and applications, such as Google Analytics, to evaluate usage of our Site. We also may use other analytic means to evaluate our Services. We use these tools to help us improve our Services, performance and user experiences. These entities may use cookies and other tracking technologies to perform their services. We do not share your personal information with these third parties.

### 9\. Third-Party Links

When you click on links on our Site, they may direct you away from our Site. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other websites and encourage you to read their individual privacy policies. If you visit a third-party website or mobile application link from our Site, you do so at your own risk.

### 10\. How You Can Access Your Information. 

Although we describe much of the following processes throughout this Privacy Policy, please do not hesitate to email us at editor@linuxhint.com to receive the following information:

What personal information pertaining to you is being processed  
Why this information is being processed  
Who has access to this personal information about you  
How this personal information is being used in automated decisions  
What processes are using this information

### 11\. Opting Out of Emails

We may send periodic promotional or informational emails to you. You may opt-out of such communications by following the opt-out instructions contained in the email. Please note that it may take up to 10 business days for us to process opt-out requests. If you opt-out of receiving emails about recommendations or other information we think may interest you, we may still send you emails your use of the Services you have requested or received from us.

### 12\. Children. 

The Services are not intended for use by children under the age of 13. Linux Hint does not allow individuals under the age of 13 to provide any information to us, nor do we knowingly collect or use any personal information from such children. If you are under the age of 13, do not submit any information to our Site. If we learn that we collected personal information from children under the age of 13, we will take steps to delete that information as soon as possible.

### 13\. International Data Transfer.

Linux Hint is a United States company. The Services are intended for use globally, however, if you access the Services and/or provide information to Linux Hint while outside of the U.S., Linux Hint transfers and stores personal information to the United States for processing. The U.S. may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided the information. When we transfer your information to the U.S., we will protect it as described in this Privacy Policy. By visiting the Site, using our Services or providing Linux Hint with any information, you fully understand and unambiguously consent to this transfer, processing and storage of your information in the United States.

We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our Site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features in an effort to prevent loss, theft and unauthorized access, use and disclosure.

### 14\. California Residents Privacy Rights.

Pursuant to California Civil Code Section 1798.83, California residents who provide us with personal information in obtaining services for personal, family, or household use are entitled to request and obtain from us, one time per calendar year, information about the customer information we shared, if any, with other businesses for their own direct marketing uses. Alternatively, the law provides that a company may comply, as Linux Hint does, by disclosing in its privacy policy that it provides user choice (opt-in or opt-out) regarding sharing personal information with third parties for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes, and information on how to exercise that choice. As stated above in this Privacy Policy, Linux Hint provides you a choice prior to sharing your personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. If you do not opt-in or if you choose to opt-out at the time Linux Hint offers that choice, Linux Hint does not share your information with that identified third party for its direct marketing purposes.

If you are a California resident and you have questions about our practices with respect to sharing information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes and your ability to exercise choice, please send your request to editor@linuxhint.com.

### 15\. Changes to Privacy Policy. 

If our Privacy Policy or procedures change, we will immediately post those changes on our Site. You can access our most recent Privacy Policy on https://www.linuxhint.com Any such changes will be effective immediately upon being posted, unless otherwise stated in the change.

### 16\. Effective Date. 

This Privacy Policy is effective as of January 7, 2019.

### 17\. Amazon Affiliate

We are a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for us to earn fees by linking to Amazon.com and affiliated sites.

### 18\. Google Partner

We are a participant in Google AdSense Program. We are a participant in Google Analytics Program in order to understand user behavior on our site. These are standard offerings from Google for publishers. Please see Google’s [policy on Privacy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).

### 19\. Adthrive

This Site is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site. AdThrive uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates. We publish interest-based advertisements on the Site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, AdThrive, Google and our other advertising partners will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies. 

A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed. Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third party partners. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/). However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained. 

For European Economic Area Residents

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing. If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site, you can contact us at [editor@linuxhint.com](mailto:editor@linuxhint.com) and contact AdThrive at [info@adthrive.com](mailto:info@adthrive.com). If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences link at the bottom of the site. (Available in the EU.)

For questions or inquiries please contact us:  
**  
Linux Hint LLC  
19925 Stevens Creek Blvd #100  
Cupertino, CA 95014  
408-827-3420  
editor@linuxhint.com**
